version=pmwiki-2.0.beta26
newline=²
time=1111872561
text=PmWiki has the ability to output [[RSS(#huh)]]v1 or [[RSS(#huh)]]v2 documents by adding the line² [=²        include_once('scripts/rss.php');²=]²somewhere in your @@config.php@@ and supplying @@?action=rss@@ in the URL to a RSS aggregator (@@?action=rdf@@ will output RSS v1).²²!!!How does it work?²²This feature builds on the WikiTrails idea.  The page that is browsed with @@?action=rss@@ is treated as a [[WikiTrail(s)]].  The trail page becomes the channel in the RSS document and each item on the trail become items in the RSS output.  One can use the RecentChanges or Main.AllRecentChanges pages as source WikiTrails, thus providing RSS feeds of new items for each WikiGroup and the entire site.  However, note that any `WikiTrail will work, thus individuals can create feeds for custom pages.²²!!!What is this good for?²²RSS stands for Really Simple Syndication.  The idea is that certain web pages are analogous to published media such as newspapers (some are more than analogous, they ''are'' newspapers :-).  Periodically the web page is updated with new content and rather than push the entire content to the reader, the reader can use RSS to get just the headlines and links to the full content.  In PmWiki-land, one of the pages that is updated in this fashion is the RecentChanges.  Oddly enough it can also be used as a [[WikiTrail(s)]] and thus you can get an [[http://www.pmwiki.org/wiki/Main/RecentChanges?action=rss|RSS feed]] of the RecentChanges.²²!!!What is needed to read rss feeds?²A ''news aggregator'' is a piece of software to enable the display of rss feeds. There are some which work as extensons to browsers, and others which work as part of email clients. See Wikipedia:News_aggregator for a list of available software.²²[[#huh]]²!!!What's the difference between [=RSSv1=] and [=RSSv2=]?²Glad you asked!  Back when the whole idea of RSS was invented it stood for RDF Site Summary where RDF stands for Resource Description Framework.  Basically RDF was a way to describe meta-information about content using XML.  The only problem with RSS back then was that it had very little to do with RDF (RDF headers were output, but the rest of the document was different XML than what RDF defined).  So, anyway, this idea of RSS evolved for a time and gave birth to [[RSS]]v1.²²Sometime later Dave Winer decided to redo the RSS spec and gave the acronym a new meaning--Really Simple Syndication.  Thus was born [[RSS]]v2 which was quite different from [[RSS]]v1 but still trying to accomplish the same goals.²²%trail%<<|PmWiki.DocumentationIndex|>>²²
targets=PmWiki.RSS,PmWiki.PmWiki,PmWiki.WikiTrails,PmWiki.RecentChanges,Main.AllRecentChanges,PmWiki.WikiGroup,PmWiki.RefCount,PmWiki.AvailableActions,PmWiki.DocumentationIndex
author=Pm
name=PmWiki.RSS
host=24.1.28.47
agent=Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.7.6) Gecko/20050317 Firefox/1.0.2
rev=20
